

Aleš TRUNDA

Front-end developer

PROFILE

I started in IT years ago as a solo freelancer working on small projects. Since I'm very interested in self-development and learning, I've worked my way up to large projects used by thousands of users every day.

I made my first web pages as a school project back in 2006. Since then I've been involved in hundreds of web projects across multiple industries.

LANGUAGE **SKILLS**

Czech - native speaker English - B2 German - basic level

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

driving license - B

CONTACT

- alestrunda.eu
- ✓ alestrunda@gmail.com
- **\(+420 606 516 133**
- S alestrunda
- in linkedin.com/in/ales-trunda/
- github.com/alestrunda

EDUCATION

University 2015 - 2019 PALACKÝ UNIVERSITY in Olomouc - Department of Computer Science

BSc degree. Thesis: Educational application Vocabulary Scholar. Made as web app in React and mobile app in React Native. Published on Google Play, graded A.

High school 2005 - 2009

Gymnázium JIŘÍHO WOLKERA, Prostějov Final exam fields: Czech, Mathematics, English, Information Technology

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer

2021 - present

- Labster ApS (remote)
- one of the 3 frontend developers in a team of 10
- responsibilities: development, code review, writing E2E & unit tests, maintenance, setting best practices, mentoring
- technologies: vue.js, tailwind, sass, typescript, SSG (Gridsome), Nuxt.js, jest, cypress. Netlify, Contentful, Datadog...
- Software Engineer

2020 - 2021

SolarWinds Czech, s.r.o. (on-site in Brno, Czech Republic)

- full-stack
- worked on product "Loggly" (SAAS)
- team of 12 developers in front-end plus several more in back-end and QA teams
- responsibilities: development, maintenance, code reviews, cooperation with other teams, customer support, interviews (interviewed 7 applicants), security
- wide range of technologies: Python, Django, React, Typescript, SASS, REST API, GraphQL, WebSockets, JWT, Docker, node.js, AWS...
- Front-end Developer

2019 - 2020

QCM s.r.o. (on-site in Brno, Czech Republic)

- worked a new form application for the government
- created a solution to automatically generate forms based on custom yml syntax
- created more than 15 forms with complex logic
- responsibilities: architecture, development, cooperation with back-end developers, code reviews, mentoring
- technologies: React, Typescript, SASS, Bootstrap, Material-UI, REST API, react testing library, Storybook
- Front-end and WordPress Developer

2014 - present (part-time since 2019)

Self-employed, contractor

- worked as a contractor for dozens of web studios and startups
- teamed up with other freelancers
- $\bullet \ \ developed \ web \ sites, applications, e-shops, HTML5 \ games, new sletters, an imated$ banners.
- responsibilities: architecture and development, cooperation with other developers, consulting, customer issues
- wide variety of technologies: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, gulp, jQuery, Vue.js, Bootstrap, ITCSS, rest API, Latte, WordPress, Woocommerce. • worked with/for: WSB, Media Solution s.r.o., Kreatura digital s.r.o., Creative
- Studio s.r.o., Atreo Digital s.r.o. etc.
- Front-end Developer

2014 - 2015

- Self-employed
- ThemeForest templates developer
- published 7 HTML templates, one jQuery game
- more than 1500 sales in total
- teamed up with a couple of other authors from all around the world
- responsibilities: developing HTML templates from PSD templates and selling them on ThemeForest, client support, documentation, cooperation with other authors

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Front-End

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT

JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, SPA, React.js, Redux, Vue, jQuery, Babel. HTML5, CSS3, SASS, ITCSS (BEM), RWD, Tailwind, Bootstrap. Jest, react testing library, Cypress.

Back-End

JAM stack, WORDPRESS & WOOCOMMERCE ${\sf Node.js,\,Python,\,PHP,\,MYSQL,\,NoSQL\,(MongoDB),\,GraphQL,\,REST\,API}$ Though I'm involved in full-stack development, I mainly focus on front-end.

Miscellaneous

Working in team, code quality, project management etc. Git, Slack, Trello, Jira. AWS, Docker. Automated tests, CI/CD. Webpack, npm, yarn, gulp. Prettier, ESLint, stylelint. React Native Figma, Abstract, Photoshop, Illustrator, Avocode.

Last update 22.02.2022